drew@drewmyers.io (3.

(330)749-7335

https://drewmyers.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/drewmyerslin/

Profile

Enthusiastic Full Stack Software Developer with 6+ years of experience, including team leadership. Key successes include decreasing UI feature lead time for primary web app by 150%, and leadership in development and deployment of a modern resilient k8s architecture that reduced downtime by >300%. An enthusiastic team player with a passion for user and developer experience.

Skills

React, Redux, Angular, Node.js, Typescript, Javascript, CSS, Kubernetes, Docker, Serverless, AWS, NoSQL, Mongo, Couchbase, Java, Kotlin, Clojure, Python, Linux/UNIX, Agile

Experience

DEVELOPMENT SQUAD LEAD, IBM – 2018-PRESENT

Lead an Agile team of 5. Gathered requirements and wrote user stories, conducted daily stand-ups in two-week Iterations, conducted sprint reviews, retrospectives, and sprint planning. Developed the roadmap for our squad to continuously improve velocity and decrease lead time on new features.

Spearheaded project to overhaul codebase of SPA web app. Decreased lead time for features by 150%, increased unit test coverage from <10% to near 100% and greatly reduced costly timing and state-management bugs.

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, IBM - 2015-2018

Tech lead on project to develop a "modern" application that would drive requirements for common k8s platform. Produced a stateless k8s microservices architecture that reduced downtime by >300%, lowered operations costs by an order of magnitude and is now used as a reference architecture for the common k8s platform.

Designed and implemented stateless JWT-based authentication scheme for SSO between applications. JWT-based scheme increased performance by eliminating server-side session and reducing chattiness between UIs and backend. Scheme passed several rounds of penetration testing and became reference authentication implementation for our business unit.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, IBM - 2013-2015

Lead a team of 3 interns to expose REST APIs on legacy Java product, which was a crucial aspect of a project that lead to >\$10 million sales.

Dockerized legacy monolithic Java application, cutting down on startup time down from >5 mins to about 30 seconds and reducing install time from >1 hour to instantaneous.

Education

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH, B.E. in Electrical & Computer Engineering, 2013